O'Connell, Francis A. Papers 5774
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Francis A. O'Connell Papers
1959-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
O'Connell, Francis A.
5774
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Speeches, collective labor agreements, correspondence and lecture notes
3338451
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 20, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1
Collective bargaining--United States.; Management rights--United States.; Personnel management--United States.; Industrial relations. United States. Addresses, essays, lectures.; O'Connell, Francis A.,1914-; Olin Corporation.
3338451
- Series I: Speeches/Conferences (1959-1976) (Box 1)
- "A Critical Look at Labor Arbitration Today. ", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Industrial Relations Association. Buffalo, NY. 9/8/59.
- Olin Corp.: Joint Staff - Operating Division Heads., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  University Club 3/3/60.
- "Contract Negotiations - Pitfalls and Pointers.", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Labor-Management Seminar: West Virginia University. 4/21/60.
- "Labor Arbitration, 1960: Panacea or Pickpocket?" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  American Management Association (AMA) Fall Personnel Conference. 9/27/60.
- "Critical Clauses in Your Labor Contract.", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  National Association of Broadcasters. Washington D.C. 5/10/61.
- "Arbitration of Work Rules Issues.", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Dusquesne University. Pittsburgh, PA. 5/11/61.
- "Arbitration as a Legal Process.", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  AMA Seminar. Astor, NY. 6/6/61.
- "Current Problems in Collective Bargaining.", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Personnel Administrators of Baltimore. Baltimore, MD. 10/18/61.
- "Contracting Out.", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Paper Mill Meeting, Atlanta, GA 10/30/61.
- National Metal Trades Association Conference, Seminar #1., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  New York, NY 2/19-21/61.
- "What is the Future of Labor Arbitration?", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Federal Bar Association. New York, NY 2/20/62.
- "Labor-Management Perspective.", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Houston Personnel Association. Houston, TX. 4/11/62.
- "Uses and Limitations of Arbitration in Settling Automation Disputes.", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  New York, NY. 5/10/62.
- "The Vanishing Right To Manage.", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Joint-Staff Operating Division Heads Meeting. 6/11/62.
- "Arbitration Procedure and Practice.", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  New York University 15th Annual Conference on Labor. New York, NY. 6/13/62.
- "The Vanishing Right To Manage.", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  California Personnel Management Association. Los Angeles, CA. 8/16/62.
- "TVRTM - And What Can Be Done About It.*, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  National Flexible Packaging Association. Waldorf Astoria, NY. 10/2/62.
- "The Vanishing Right To Manage.*, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Olin Management Club. New Haven, CN. 10/4/62.
- Metals Division Industrial Relations., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Gulfport, MS. 10/23-24/62.
- "The Vanishing Right To Manage., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Society for Advancement of Management. Joliet, IL. 10/30/62.
- "The Vanishing Right To Manage.", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Pennsylvania Society for Professional Engineers. Philadelphia, PA. 11/1/62.
- "New Dimensions in Collective Bargaining and What's Wrong With Them.", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  New School. New York, N.Y 12/12/62.
- "TVRTM - And What Can Be Done About It., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Western North Carolina Chapter of Society for Advancement of Management. Pisah Forest. 1/16/63.
- National Petroleum Refiners Association Conference -Panel Discussion., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Philadelphia, PA. 3/6/63.
- "New Dimensions in Collective Bargaining and What's Wrong With Them., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Industrial Personnel Club. Chattanoga, TN. 3/14/63.
- "Some Recent Failures of Collective Bargaining - A Look at How and Why.", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  New York, NY. 4/17/63.
- "Some Recent Failures of Collective Bargaining - A Look at How and Why.", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  New York, NY. 5/21/63.
- "Plant Removal Under the NLRA.", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  New York University Annual Conference on Labor. New York, NY. 6/10/63.
- "Current Crises in Collective Bargaining - And What It Means to Management., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  General Managers Meeting. 6/63.
- Chemicals Division/Olin Corp., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Chicago, IL 9/19/63.
- "Anticipating Major Employer Changes - Implications for Collective Bargaining.", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Cornell University. Ithaca, NY. 11/13/63.
- "The Right to Manage: Lost Strayed or Stolen?", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Society for Advancement of Management. Pittsburgh, PA. 11/21/63.
- "Increasing Management's Arbitration Potency.", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  36th NAM Institute on Industrial Relations. FL 3/8-13/64..
- Discussion of Decision Bargaining., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  NLRB Conference. 4/64.
- "Handling Employee Grievances and Arbitration. ", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Manufacturers Association of Connecticut. New Haven, CT. 9/10/64.
- "Arbitration v. Negotiation in Automation Disputes.*, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  NPRA. Casper, WY. 9/30/64.
- "The Right To Manage: Lost Strayed or Stolen?", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Pittsburgh, PA. 11/19/64.
- "Handling of Arbitration Cases.", 1964 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  MCA, Chemical Industrial Relations Symposium. Houston, TX. 12/15/64.
- "IRS - The Inflexible Duty to Bargain, (commentary on Fireboard and GE>.", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  New York, NY. 1/21/65.
- "The Labor Arbitrator: Judge or Legislator. ", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  National Arbitration Association. 1/29/65.
- "The Right To Manage: Lost, Strayed or Stolen?", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Yale University Management Conference. 3/31/65.
- "Preparation and Trial of Arbitration Cases.", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Milwaukee, WI. 4/7/65.
- "The Duty To Bargain: Effect of Fireboard, GE and Other Decisions on Collective Bargaining. ", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Second Annual Labor-Management Conference - Wilkes College. 4/29/65.
- "Public Control of Labor Relations. ", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  New York University. 5/13/65. Includes frame of reference questions.
- "Preparation and Trial of Arbitration Cases., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Manufacturers Association of Syracuse. Syracuse, NY. 5/19/65.
- "Current Trends in Collective Bargaining., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Silver Bay Conference. 7/14-17/65.
- National Foundry Association - Panel Discussion., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Chicago, IL 9/30/65. Includes also: "What Happened to the Right to Manage. "
- "Management Looks at its Duty to Bargain.", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Illinois State Chamber of Commerce. 9/30-10/1/65.
- "The Developing National Labor Policy.", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  American Arbitration Association. 10/12/65.
- "Subcontracting as a Mandatory Subject of Bargaining. ", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  CHI Corporate Counsel Institute. 10/15/65.
- "Equal Opportunity - And Now What?", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  New York Personnel Association. 11/3/65.
- "The Fight to Manage.", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Industrial Relations Research Association. (IRRA) Buffalo, NY. 11/17/65.
- "Where Do We Stand on Management Rights - 1966?" (Box 1, Folder 54)
  University of Michigan. 1/19/66.
- "Trade Union Democracy - Does Management Care?", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Industrial Relations Research Association. (IRRA) New York, NY. 1/20/66.
- "New Ferment in Labor-Management Relations.", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  American Management Association (AMA) Conference. Chicago, IL. 2/11/66.
- "Government Intervention in Bargaining.", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  University of Iowa. 4/26/66.
- "Labor, Management, Government - Teamwork or Trussel?", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  New Haven, CT. 4/27/66.
- "The Arbitrators, the NLRB, and the Right to Manage. ", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  St. Bonaventure University, NY. 5/7/66.
- "Labor Relations - 1966 Model... (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Southwest Area Conference on Industrial Relations. Houston, TX. 5/20/66.
- "Arbitration and NLRB - The Right to Manage., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Associated Industries of Cleveland. Cleveland, OH. 9/29/66.
- "Bargaining for the Right to Manage.", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Baltimore Chamber of Commerce. Baltimore, MD. 10/11/66.
- "The NLRB and the Right to Communicate. ", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  New York Association of Communicators. 10/27/66.
- Speech to Olin Industrial Relations and Personnel Groups., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Joliet, IL. 11/17/66.
- "NLRB's Role in Today's, Bargaining: Help or Hindrance?" NAM", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Congress of Industry. New York, NY. 12/9/66.
- "The Arbitrators, the NLRB, and the Right to Manage.", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Mountain States Employer's Council. Denver, CO. 1/24/67.
- "Government, Unions, and the Right to Manage.", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Society for Advancement of Management. Asheville, NC. 2/15/67.
- "How to Preserve the Right to Manage.", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Society for Advancement of Management. Chattanooga, TN. 3/16/67.
- "What Ails Collective Bargaining.", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Employers Association of North Jersey. 3/30/67.
- "Impact of the Workforce on Collective Bargaining., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Notre Dame Union-Management Conference. 4/7/67.
- "What Ails Collective Bargaining?", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Chattanooga, TN. 4/11/67.
- "Effect of Arbitration on Industrial Relations Practices." "Impact of Grievance Handling, including Arbitration of Contract Negotiations.", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  American Arbitration Workshop. New York, NY. 4/21/67.
- "Effect of the NLRB and Court Decisions Concerning Craft Severance, Gerrymandering of Bargaining Units, and Subcontracting.", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Chemical Industrial Relations Symposium. New Orleans, LA. 4/27/67.
- "The Need for Labor Lav Reform - the Role of the NLRB in Enhancing Union Power., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  US Chamber of Commerce. 5/2/67.
- "Is Collective Bargaining in Need of Overhaul?", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Cape Kennedy Personnel Association Industrial Relations Seminar. 5/19/67.
- "What Ails Collective Bargaining?", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  New Haven Manufacturers Association - Executive Associates Forum. New Haven, CT. 6/21/67.
- "The Drive Toward Joint Participation and Codetermination: Are We Chasing Europe or Have We Passed It?", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Texas Manufacturers Association. Houston, TX. 10/26/67.
- Fiberboard Doctrine., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  American Management Association (AMA) Annual Personnel Conference. Chicago, IL. 2/14/68.
- "Labor Relations 1968." (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Olin Corp. Board of Directors Speech. 2/29/68.
- Ervin Subcommittee on the Separation of Powers Hearings - Congressional Oversight of Administrative Agencies. (NLRB) (US Senate Committee on the Judiciary), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
  Testimony on behalf of the National Association of Manufacturers. 4/9/68.
- "The Strike.", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Niagara University Seminar on Collective Bargaining. 4/19/68.
- "The Newest Threat to the Ability to Manage., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  New York Personnel Management Association. 5/20/68.
- "Employee Relations: 1968 and Beyond." (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Olin Management Club of New Haven. New Haven, CT. 6/6/68.
- "The Labor Scene: A Dim View.", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Grinding Wheel Institute and Abrasive Grain Association - Industrial Relations Forum, NY. 10/4/68.
- "The Ever-Increasing Imbalance in Labor-Management Relations.", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Edison Electric Institute. New York, NY. 12/4/68.
- "Erosion of Management Rights.", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  NY Chamber of Commerce Conference on Labor Law Reform. New York, NY. 1/30/69.
- "National Public Policy and Labor-Management Relations/National Labor Policy and Public Interest. ", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
  American Management Association Annual Conference. New York, NY. 2/4/69.
- The Singer Company - Labor Relations Conference., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Princeton Club. 2/26/69.
- "Management Rights and Union Power.", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Institute of Electrical and Electronic Society (Eastern Shore Division). Salisbury, MD. 3/11/69.
- "The Public Interest in Labor-Management Relations: A Challenge ^to the Nixon Administration. ", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Personnel Group Southwest Connecticut Manufacturers Association. Stamford, CT. 5/12/69.
- University of San Francisco - Conference of Labor-Management School., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  10/23/69.
- "What's Ahead in Labor Relations.", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Gulf States Industrial Conference. 11/6/69.
- Manufacturing Chemists Association (MCA), NY., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  11/25/69.
- Quarter Century Club., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  12/4/69.
- "Collective Bargaining for the 70's.", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  National Association of Manufacturers. 12/4/69.
- "How to Lose Your Right to Manage Without Trying. ", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  Mountain States Employers Council, Inc. - Industrial Relations Conference. 1/27/70.
- Olin Corp. - Employee Relations Conference., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  2/3-5/70.
- "The Board, the Bias, and the Bargaining. ", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  Philadelphia, PA. 3/3/70.
- "Employee Relations in the 70's: New Influences and New Approaches.", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  Industrial Relations Research Association. New York, NY. 3/19/70.
- "Bargaining is a two-handed game.", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  Kansas City Bar Association - Labor Law Seminar. 3/25/70.
- "Employee Relations in the 70's: New Influences and New Approaches.", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Industrial Management Club of Wood County. 4/20/70.
- Collective Bargaining - 1970 and Beyond. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  Industrial Relations Society of Buffalo. Buffalo, NY. 5/12/70.
- "1970 Collective Bargaining: A Look Backward and Forward. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  Illinois Institute for Continuing Legal Education -National Law Institute. Chicago, IL. 5/14/70.
- "Trends in Labor Law., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  Institute for Collective Bargaining. 5/19/70.
- "New Problems and Approaches in Private and Public Employee Relations.*, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  AMR International. Washington, D.C. 6/11/70.
- "Labor Relations Outlook for the 70's., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  National Paint, Varnish and Lacquer Association. 9/17/70.
- "Employee Relations - A New Approach for a New Era: Why Bother to Communicate?", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  Merchants and Manufacturers Conference. 10/25/70.
- Olin Environmental Conference., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  12/7-8/70.
- "The Olin Approach to the New Era in Employee Relations.", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  NAM Institute on Industrial Relations. 3/21-25/71.
- "Conflict or Cooperation? An Academic Look at Labor -Management Objectives.", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  University of Louisville. 5/3-4/71.
- "Winds of Change: Fair Weather or Foul?", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  Reed City Area Chamber of Commerce Industrial Banquet. 5/19/71.
- "Employee Relations: A New Era, New Problems, New Solutions. ", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  Eastern North Carolina Manufacturers Association -Capitol Associated Industries, Inc. 6/14-16/71.
- Industrial Relations Association of St. Louis., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  10/13/71.
- "Collective Bargaining and the Rule of Law. ", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  Wharton School. 11/18/71.
- "Labor and Public Interest: Some Questions and Answers. ", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  Conference of Chemical Companies. San Antonio, TX. 5/4/72.
- Associated General Contractors Legal Conference., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  6/29/72.
- "Labor and Public Interest: A Problem and A Program. ", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  Employee Relations Conference - Delaware State Chamber of Commerce. 10/25/72.
- Olin Medical Conference., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  Point Clear, AL. 10/31-11/3/72.
- "Regaining the Right to Manage.", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  Central Illinois Builders of AGC. 11/18/72.
- "The Contractor's Right to Manage, the Dead Sea Scrolls, and Other Exercises in Archaeology.", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  MACMA Conference. Puerto Rico. 1/29/73.
- Boat Hall Lecture, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 62-64)
  University of California at Berkeley. 2/28/73.
- Harvard Business School Alumnae Group., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  4/19/73.
- "Labor and the Public Interest: A Problem and A Program.", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  Atlanta Paper Training Conference. Atlanta, GA. 4/26/73.
- "Olin Tackles the 70's., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  Biltmore Forest Country Club. 6/19/73.
- "Employee Relations - A Hew Era, New Problems, New Solutions.", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  Wrightsville Beach, NC. 6/26/73.
- Chemical Group Safety., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  9/18/73.
- "Contractor's Right to Manage, the Dead Sea Scrolls, and Other Exercises in Archaeology.", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  International Association of Wall and Ceiling Contractors. 2/2/74.
- National Engineering Societies Banquet., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  Lake Charles, IL. 2/21/74.
- Pace Speech - Award for Outstanding Contributions to Labor-Management Affairs., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  1/290/75.
- Series II: Cornell University Lectures, ILR 300, 1972-1974 (includes: lecture notes, drafts, clippings, correspondence, outlines, etc.) (Box 3)
- Golden Empire Economics Group., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Grass Valley, CA. 9/75.
- Chemists Club., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  10/6/75.
- Olin Awards Speech., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  11/5/75.
- "Management Rights - Old Hat or New Ball Game?*, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4-7)
  University of Texas Conference on Industrial Peace. 11/18/75.
- Connecticut Personnel Association, Inc., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  11/19/75.
- NIBCO Speech. Elkhart, ND., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  4/27/75.
- "Anticipative Management in Labor Relations, Communications, Managerial Style, and Other Areas.", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Employers Association. Milwaukee, WI. 4/8/76.
- Association of General Counsel., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Ponta Vendra, FL. 5/3/76.
- "Union Power: The Roots and the Branches.", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
  Hillsdale College. 9/21/76. Includes: "Elements of Inordinate Labor Power" draft; Statement of Reed Larson, president, National Right to Work Committee; "Big Labor and Big Strikes (NAM)"; "The Impact of the Academy in the Formation of Opinion: Some Second
- Quarter Century Club., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  11/4/76.
- Arbitration: Arbitration and Its Critics., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Arbitration: How to Arbitrate., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Arbitration: How to Prepare and Try an Arbitration Case. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Arbitration: Miscellaneous., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
- Class Information - Exams, Term Papers., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Spring, 1974.
- Correspondence - Personal and with Cornell., 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 23-26)
- Council Meeting - Cornell., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  11/19/74.
- Exam Questions - Draft., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  3/12/74.
- First Semester: Clippings, Handouts, Readings Used in Lecture, Course Outline, Required Readings, Second Semester Working Copy., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 29-34)
- Lecture Notes., 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 35-41)
- Reserve Reading Lists and Orders., 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Second Semester: Used Materials and Notes, Reading Lists, Class Lists, Exam Questions, Clippings, etc., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2-7)
- Teaching File ILR 300 - Old Drafts, etc., 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
- Miscellaneous., 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
- Series III: Virginia Polytechnic Institute. 1975-1976. Speech: Who is "The Establishment" and what is "The System"? (Box 4)
- Correspondence with VPI., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Draft., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14-16)
  2/6/75.
- Draft., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  4/1/76.
- Materials not used for VPI Speech. (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
- Notes for VPI Speech. (Box 4, Folder 21-24)
- Speech Revision. (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Speech., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
  2/10/1975
- Speech., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  5/10/76.
- Speech - Berry College Version and Supplementary Material. (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
- Speech - University of Kentucky Version., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  3/4/75.
- Series IV: UCLA Regents Professorship, 1977 (Box 4)
- Correspondence with UCLA., 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Law School Colloquium: Arbitration Outline and Issues., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 33-35)
  3/77.
- Law School Colloquium. "Prospectus for HEW Labor Legislation: A Management View.", 1977 (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
  3/8/77.
- Mason (Prof.) - Nucleus Group. (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Massarik (Prof.) -.Lecture. Notes for HR Management 250B. (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Mitchell (Prof.) - Law and Government Policy in Industrial Relations: lecture notes. (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Olin Fellows. (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Prasow (Prof. ) - Labor-Management Relations in Public and Non-Profit Sector. "Management Rights., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  2/10/77.
- Research Seminar - Micro Economics. (Seminar for Tutors) (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Taylor (Prof.) - Systems of Employee-Management Participation. (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Series V: Claremont-McKenna College Lectures, 1978 (Box 5)
- Claremont Lecture #1 - Working File., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Claremont Lecture #2 - Working File. The Negotiation Process - Legal, Economic, and Psychological Factors., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  2/15/78.
- Claremont Lecture #3 - Working File. The Role of the Manager in Collective Bargaining., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  2/16/78.
- Claremont Lecture #4 - Working Files. Capitalism Under Siege - In the Media and On the Campus: An Inquiry into the Nature of, and some Proposed Remedies for, Tensions Between Business, Media, and Academe., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4-19)
  3/15/78.
- Claremont Lectures - Miscellaneous., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20-23)
- Series VI: Miscellaneous Files, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
- Fortune Letter to Editor: re article "Archie McCardells' Absolution.", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  5/80.
- Unitek Speech File. "Managing People: How Different In the 1980's?", 1981 (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
  2/9/81.
- National Labor Relations Board (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Fanning File (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Additional Material From Oral History Interview with Koppack, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  5/24/1987
- Misc. Documents (Box 5, Folder 31)